<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
        <pubdate>20131216</pubdate>
        <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Salt Lake Area,
Utah
</title>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
          <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>ut612</othercit>
        <onlink>http://websoilsurvey.nrcs.usda.gov</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
This data set is a digital soil survey and generally is the most
detailed level of soil geographic data developed by the National
Cooperative Soil Survey. The information was prepared by digitizing
maps, by compiling information onto a planimetric correct base
and digitizing, or by revising digitized maps using remotely
sensed and other information.

This data set consists of georeferenced digital map data and
computerized attribute data. The map data are in a soil survey area
extent format and include a detailed, field verified inventory
of soils and miscellaneous areas that normally occur in a repeatable
pattern on the landscape and that can be cartographically shown at
the scale mapped. A special soil features layer (point and line
features) is optional. This layer displays the location of features
too small to delineate at the mapping scale, but they are large
enough and contrasting enough to significantly influence use and
management. The soil map units are linked to attributes in the
National Soil Information System relational database, which gives
the proportionate extent of the component soils and their properties.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
SSURGO depicts information about the kinds and distribution of
soils on the landscape. The soil map and data used in the SSURGO
product were prepared by soil scientists as part of the National
Cooperative Soil Survey.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Digital versions of hydrography, cultural features, and other
associated layers that are not part of the SSURGO data set may be
available from the primary organization listed in the Point of
Contact.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020307</begdate>
          <enddate>20131216</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-112.251</westbc>
        <eastbc>-111.593</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.922</northbc>
        <southbc>40.414</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>soil survey</themekey>
        <themekey>soils</themekey>
        <themekey>Soil Survey Geographic</themekey>
        <themekey>SSURGO</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</placekt>
        <placekey>Utah</placekey>
        <placekey>Salt Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>Saltair NE Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Farmington Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Plug Peak SE Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Antelope Island South Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Saltair Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Salt Lake City North Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Fort Douglas Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Mountain Dell Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Big Dutch Hollow Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Farnsworth Peak Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Magna Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Salt Lake City South Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Sugar House Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Mount Aire Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Park City West Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Bingham Canyon Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Lark Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Midvale Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Draper Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Lowe Peak Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Tickville Spring Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Jordan Narrows Quadrangle</placekey>
        <placekey>Lehi Quadrangle</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>
The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation
Service, should be acknowledged as the data source in products
derived from these data.

This data set is not designed for use as a primary regulatory tool
in permitting or citing decisions, but may be used as a reference
source. This is public information and may be interpreted by
organizations, agencies, units of government, or others based on
needs; however, they are responsible for the appropriate
application. Federal, State, or local regulatory bodies are not to
reassign to the Natural Resources Conservation Service any
authority for the decisions that they make. The Natural Resources
Conservation Service will not perform any evaluations of these maps
for purposes related solely to State or local regulatory programs.

Photographic or digital enlargement of these maps to scales greater
than at which they were originally mapped can cause misinterpretation
of the data. If enlarged, maps do not show the small areas of
contrasting soils that could have been shown at a larger scale. The
depicted soil boundaries, interpretations, and analysis derived from
them do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling, testing, and
detailed study of specific sites for intensive uses. Thus, these data
and their interpretations are intended for planning purposes only.
Digital data files are periodically updated. Files are dated, and
users are responsible for obtaining the latest version of the data.
</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>State Soil Scientist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>NRCS</address>
          <address>Federal Building, Room 4010</address>
          <address>125 South State</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>UT</state>
          <postal>84138-1100</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-524-4574</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>800-877-8339</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>801-524-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Mike.Domeier@ut.usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The attribute accuracy is tested by manual
comparison of the source with hard copy plots and/or symbolized
display of the map data on an interactive computer graphic system.
Selected attributes that cannot be visually verified on plots or
on screen are interactively queried and verified on screen. In
addition, the attributes are tested against a master set of valid
attributes. All attribute data conform to the attribute codes in
the signed classification and correlation document and amendment(s).
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
Certain node/geometry and topology GT- polygon/chain relationships
are collected or generated to satisfy topological requirements
(the GT-polygon corresponds to the soil delineation). Some of these
requirements include: chains must begin and end at nodes, chains
must connect to each other at nodes, chains do not extend through
nodes, left and right GT-polygons are defined for each chain
element and are consistent throughout, and the chains representing
the limits of the file are free of gaps. The tests of logical
consistency are performed using vendor software. All internal
polygons are tested for closure with vendor software and are checked
on hard copy plots. All data are checked for common soil lines (i.e.,
adjacent polygons with the same label). Edge locations generally do
not deviate from centerline to centerline by more than 0.01 inch.
The boundary of this survey is matched to the adjacent SSURGO
certified surveys of Davis-Weber Area, Utah; Morgan Area, Utah -
Morgan County and Part of Weber County; Summit Area, Utah, Parts of
Summit, Salt Lake, and Wasatch Counties; Utah County, Utah - Central
Part; Fairfield-Nephi Area, Utah; and Toole Area, Utah - Tooele County and Parts of Box Elder,
Davis and Juab Counties, Utah White Pine and Elko Counties, Nevada.
Feature edges and labels do not match.
</logic>
    <complete>
A map unit is a collection of areas defined and named in terms of
their soil components or miscellaneous areas or both. Each map
unit differs in some respect from all others in a survey area and
each map unit has a symbol that uniquely identifies the map unit
on a soil map. Each individual area, point, or line so identified
on the map is a delineation.

Soil Scientists identify small areas of soils or miscellaneous areas
that have properties and behavior significantly different than the
named soils in the surrounding map unit. These minor components
may be indicated as special features. If they have a minimal effect
on use and management, or could not be precisely located, they may
not be indicated on the map.

A map unit has specified kinds of soils or miscellaneous areas
(map unit components), each with a designated range in
proportionate extent. Map units include one or more kinds of soil
or miscellaneous area. Miscellaneous areas are areas that have little
or no recognizable soil.

Specific National Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures
were used in the classification of soils, design and name of map
units, and location of special soil features. These standards are
outlined in Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993,
USDA, NRCS; Agricultural Handbook 436, Soil Taxonomy, 1995,
USDA, NRCS; and all Amendments; Keys to Soil Taxonomy,
(current issue) USDA, NRCS; National Soil Survey
Handbook, title 430-VI,(current issue) USDA, NRCS.

The actual composition and interpretive purity of the map unit
delineations were based on data collected by scientists during
the course of preparing the soil maps. Adherence to National
Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures is based on
peer review, quality control, and quality assurance. Quality
control is outlined in the memorandum of understanding for the
soil survey area and in documents that reside with the Natural
Resources Conservation Service state soil scientist. Four kinds
of map units are used in soil surveys: consociations, complexes,
associations, and undifferentiated groups.

Consociations - Consociations are named for the dominant soil.
In a consociation, delineated areas use a single name from the
dominant component in the map unit. Dissimilar components are
minor in extent. The soil component in a consociation may be
identified at any taxonomic level. Soil series is the lowest
taxonomic level. A consociation that is named as a miscellaneous
area is dominantly that kind of area and minor components do not
significantly affect the use of the map unit. The total amount of
dissimilar inclusions of other components in a map unit generally
does not exceed about 15 percent if limiting and 25 percent if
nonlimiting. A single component of a dissimilar limiting inclusion
generally does not exceed 10 percent if very contrasting.

Complexes and associations - Complexes and associations consist
of two or more  dissimilar components that occur in a regularly
repeating pattern. The total amount of other dissimilar components
is minor extent. The following arbitrary rule determines whether
complex or association is used in the name. The major components
of an association can be separated at the scale of mapping. In
either case, because the major components are sufficiently different
in morphology or behavior, the map unit cannot be called a
consociation. In each delineation of a complex or an association,
each major component is normally present though their proportions
may vary appreciably from one delineation to another. The total
amount of inclusions in a map unit that are dissimilar to any of
the major components does not exceed 15 percent if limiting and
25 percent if nonlimiting. A single kind of dissimilar limiting
inclusion usually does not exceed 10 percent.

Undifferentiated groups - Undifferentiated groups consist of two
or more components that are not consistently associated
geographically and, therefore, do not always occur together in
the same map delineation. These components are included in the
same named map unit because their use and management are the same
or very similar for common uses. Generally they are grouped together
because some common feature, such as steepness, stoniness, or
flooding, determines their use and management. If two or more
additional map units would serve no useful purpose, they may be
included in the same unit. Each delineation has at least one of the
major components, and some may have all of them. The same principles
regarding the proportion of minor components that apply to
consociations also apply to undifferentiated groups. The same
principles regarding proportion of inclusion apply to
undifferentiated groups as to consociations.

Minimum documentation consists of three complete soil profile
descriptions that are collected for each soil added to the legend,
one additional per 3,000 acres mapped; three 10 observation
transects for each map unit, one additional 10 point transect per
3,000 acres.

A defined standard or level of confidence in the interpretive
purity of the map unit delineations is attained by adjusting the
kind and intensity of field investigations. Field investigations
and data collection are carried out in sufficient detail to name
map units and to identify accurately and consistently areas of
about 5 acres in areas of 2nd order survey, and about 10 acres in
areas of 3rd order survey.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The accuracy of these digital data is based upon their
compilation to base maps that meet National Map
Accuracy Standards at a scale of 1 inch equals 1,000
feet. The difference in positional accuracy between the
soil boundaries and special soil features locations in the
field and their digitized map locations is unknown. The
locational accuracy of soil delineations on the ground varies
with the transition between map units.

For example, on long gently sloping landscapes the transition
occurs gradually over many feet. Where landscapes change
abruptly from steep to level, the transition will be very
narrow. Soil delineation boundaries and special soil features
generally were digitized within 0.01 inch of their locations on
the digitizing source. The digital map elements are edge matched
between data sets. The data along each quadrangle edge are
matched against the data for the adjacent quadrangle. Edge
locations generally do not deviate from centerline to centerline
by more than 0.01 inch.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation
Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>1974</pubdate>
            <title>Soil Survey of Salt Lake Area, Utah</title>
            <geoform>atlas</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Government Printing Office</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>20000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1974</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SCS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
information for soil map unit delineations,
special soil feature locations, and data on soil properties
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1973-1977</pubdate>
            <title>multiple orthophotographs</title>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Denver, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1977</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>compilation base imagery</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>annotated overlays</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1999</begdate>
              <enddate>2001</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>compilation dates</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>compilation base / scanning source</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1955-1991</pubdate>
            <title>multiple 7.5 minute topographic quadrangles</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Menlo Park, California</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2001</begdate>
              <enddate>2001</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>compilation base reference</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>digitized soil survey of Salt Lake Area, Utah</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2001</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>digitizing date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>ARC/INFO coverage digital files</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>1998</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Tooele
Area, Utah - Toole County and Parts of Box Elder, Davis, and
Juab Counties, Utah White Pine and Elko Counties, Nevada
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1998</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>1999</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Utah
County, Utah - Central Part
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1999</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS4</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Davis-Weber
Area, Utah
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2000</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS5</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for
Fairfield-Nephi Area, Utah
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2000</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS6</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2001</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Morgan
Area, Utah - Morgan County and Part of Weber County
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial
Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2001</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS7</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
            <title>National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base</title>
            <geoform>unknown</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2004</begdate>
              <enddate>2004</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NASIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>attribute (tabular) information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Salt Lake
Area, Utah
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U. S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2004</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS8</srccitea>
        <srccontr>certified SSURGO data used for revisions</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Summit
Area, Utah, Parts of Summit, Salt Lake and Wasatch Counties
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U. S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2004</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS9</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
certified SSURGO data used for survey boundary
edge matching
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>20051208</pubdate>
            <title>
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Salt Lake
Area, Utah
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Worth, Texas</pubplace>
              <publish>
U. S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2005</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS10</srccitea>
        <srccontr>certified SSURGO data used for revisions</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple 7.5 minute digital orthophotographic quadrangles</title>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah</pubplace>
              <publish>
State of Utah, Division of Information Technology
Services, Automated Geographic Reference Center (AGRC)
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>downloaded from Utah AGRC website</othercit>
            <onlink>http://agrc.its.state.ut.us/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>1993</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>1997</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
base material for digital review and editing
of soil lines
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
            <title>multiple 7.5 minute digital raster graphics</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah</pubplace>
              <publish>
State of Utah, Division of Information Technology
Services, Automated Geographic Reference Center (AGRC)
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>downloaded from Utah AGRC website</othercit>
            <onlink>http://agrc.its.state.ut.us/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1962</begdate>
              <enddate>1985</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>
publication date of USGS
topographic quadrangles
</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS4</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
base material for delineating Great Salt Lake
historic level (4200 ft)
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</origin>
            <pubdate>2003</pubdate>
            <title>Landsat 7 satellite imagery</title>
            <edition>P38R31, P38R32</edition>
            <geoform>remote sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Logan, Utah</pubplace>
              <publish>
Utah State University, Intermountain Region Digital
Image Archive Center (IRDIAC)
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>downloaded from IRDIAC website</othercit>
            <onlink>http://earth.gis.usu.edu/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>1000000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20030521</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NASA1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
source material for supervised classification;
resulting classification used as base material for digital review
and editing of soil lines
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>Arc shapefiles for the survey of Salt Lake Area, Utah</title>
            <geoform>digital vector data</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2009</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>2009</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS11</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
digital information containing area and special
soil features for evaluation
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>2009</pubdate>
            <title>
National Soil Information System (NASIS) database for
Salt Lake Area, Utah
</title>
            <geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Fort Collins, Colorado</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service, Information Technology Center
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2009</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>export certification date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS12</srccitea>
        <srccontr>map unit legend used for comparison to spatial map unit labels</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>Region 8 soils geodatabase</title>
            <geoform>file geodatabase</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>vector digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2006</begdate>
              <enddate>2012</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>SSURGO publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NRCS13</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source of digital revision</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Field procedures for second and third order soil survey were
utilized to plot soil boundaries by field observations and by
interpreting remotely sensed data. Boundaries were verified at
closely spaced intervals and the soils in each delineation were
identified by traversing and transecting the landscape. Soil
scientists described and sampled the soils and analyzed samples
in the laboratory. The classification and correlation of map unit
names was finalized in August 1967, and the Soil Survey of Salt
Lake Area, Utah was published in 1974 at a scale of 1:20,000.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>SCS1, USGS1</srcused>
        <procdate>1974</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Information on field maps was compiled to annotated overlays,
using 1:24,000 orthophoto quadrangles and 7.5 minute topographic
quadrangles as a base reference.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>USGS1, USGS2, NRCS1</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Annotated overlays were raster scanned and converted to vector
format using R2V software for Windows NT. Soils and special
feature symbols were hand digitized from 1:24,000 scale annotated
overlays. Digital processing and editing were performed using
ARC/INFO version 7.2.1. The soil survey boundary was edge matched
to the adjacent SSURGO certified soil survey boundaries of
Davis-Weber Area, Utah; Utah County, Utah - Central Part;
Fairfield-Nephi Area, Utah; Morgan Area, Utah - Morgan County
and Part of Weber County; Toole Area, Utah - Tooele County and
Parts of Box Elder, Davis and Juab Counties, Utah, White Pine and
Elko Counties, Nevada. Custom AMLs were operated for error
identification and the data were written to DLG-3 Optional
format. Cartographic technicians at the NRCS Regional Digitizing
Center in Salina, Kansas completed the digitizing work and review
for adherence to SSURGO standards.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>
NRCS1, NRCS2, NRCS3, NRCS4,
NRCS5, NRCS6, NRCS7
</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
In the total acres for Salt Lake Area, Utah, there is a
discrepancy of approximately 61,260 acres between the spatial
acres (399,381) and the NASIS acres (460,641). This discrepancy
was caused by a portion of the Great Salt Lake not being included
into the spatial area and the map unit symbols "PT" and "UL" were
calculated into the NASIS acres but not the spatial acres.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS2</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The National Soil Information System database was developed by
NRCS soil scientists according to national standards and
specifications.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS2</srcused>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist
or delegate, upon completion of data quality verification,
determined that the tabular data should be released for official
use. A selected set of map units and components in the soil
survey legend was copied to a staging database, and rating values
for selected interpretations were generated. The list of selected
interpretations is stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20040209</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist
or delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map
units link to map units in the tabular database, and certified
the joined data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A
system assigned version number and date stamp were added and the
data were copied to the data warehouse. The tabular data for the
map units and components were extracted from the data warehouse
and reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, then
stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to the
Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20040209</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The spatial data for this survey area have been revised to
add two soil map unit delineations. A polygon labeled 'UL' was
added to the Salt Lake City North, Fort Douglas, Salt Lake City
South and Sugar House quadrangles. A polygon labeled 'PT' was
added to the Bingham Canyon and Lark quadrangles. Also during
this revision, the extent of the soil survey boundary was matched
to that of the adjacent SSURGO certified survey of Summit Area,
Utah, Parts of Summit, Salt Lake and Wasatch Counties. Editing
and review for adherence to SSURGO standards were done by
cartographic staff at the NRCS Regional Digitizing Center in
Salina, Kansas, using ArcGIS version 8.3. The certified data were
uploaded to the NRCS Soil Data Warehouse for archiving and
distribution.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS8, NRCS9</srcused>
        <procdate>2004</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20041220</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20041228</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20051207</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20051208</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Landsat scenes from P38R31 and P38R32, May 21, 2003 were mosaicked
together, and the area of wet and saline soils adjacent to the
Great Salt Lake was subset from the mosaicked image. A supervised
classification of land cover types was performed using the fuzzy
classification algorithm and the fuzzy convolution filter options
in ERDAS Imagine. Land cover types were related to soil types. The
resulting classification was field validated with an accuracy
assessment, and used as base material for updating soil lines. All
image processing and analysis was completed by a soil scientist.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS10, NASA1</srcused>
        <procdate>2003</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The data were imported into ArcMap by a soil scientist in the Utah
State University (USU) Soil Survey Satellite Office in Logan,
Utah. Soil lines were edited on screen in ArcMap, referencing the
digital orthophoto quadrangles, digital raster graphics, and
Landsat 7 supervised classification. Only the portion of the
survey area adjacent to the Great Salt Lake was updated. All new
map units in the updated portion of the survey area were given
symbols containing all capital letters. Adjustments were made to
the soil lines and labels along the survey boundary in the updated
portion of the survey area by an NRCS soil scientist to achieve a
perfect join with surrounding Utah soil survey areas. Labeling and
error checking were done in ArcMap. Adjustments to the survey area
boundary were made to include previously excluded parts of the
Great Salt Lake in the survey area. A personal geodatabase was
submitted to the NRCS Kansas Digitizing Unit for SSURGO review.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS 10, USGS3, USGS4, NASA1</srcused>
        <procdate>2006</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
SSURGO review was performed by cartographic staff at the NRCS
Digitizing Unit in Salina, Kansas. The files were evaluated using
ArcGIS version 8.3 and the January 2006 SSURGO Evaluation AMLs
provided by NCGC. The certified data were uploaded to the NRCS
Soil Data Warehouse for archiving and distribution.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS10</srcused>
        <procdate>2006</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20061211</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil
Scientist or delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map
units link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned version
number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to the data warehouse.
Data elements were updated, and validated in 2006 to accommodate current modeling
needs. The tabular data for the map units and components were extracted from the
data warehouse and reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, then stored
in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20061211</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The tabular data were extracted from the data mart without change.
The spatial data's coordinate system was transformed to UTM Zone 12, Northern Hemisphere
(NAD 83) using ESRI ArcObjects 8.3 "ConvertFeatureClass" and exported to an ESRI shapefile.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20091019</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The survey-wide Arc shapefiles from the online SSURGO data were
imported to ARC/INFO 9.2 by certification staff at the Montana
Digitizing Unit. Evaluation macros of June 2004 were applied to the
data. Map unit labels were compared to an approved map unit legend
from the National Soil Information System data base. ArcGIS was
used to join to adjacent survey boundaries and verify previous
adjacent survey joins. The data were uploaded to the soil data
warehouse staging server.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS11, NRCS12</srcused>
        <procdate>20091019</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20100210</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20100210</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The spatial data for the Soil Survey of Salt Lake Area, Utah
was downloaded from the Soil Data Mart on October 15, 2012.  The
individual shapefiles were appended into a geodatabase for Region 8.
The data were processed in ARCGIS 10.1 using a topology object with
a 0.1 meter cluster tolerance for the purpose of eliminating gaps and
overlaps within the Region 8 soils geodatabase.  Individual soil
survey area data were exported as shapefiles from the regional
geodatabase.  A datum transformation from NAD83 to WGS84 using the
NAD_1983_To_WGS_1984_1 datum transformation method was applied to
the data.  The data were checked with the SSURGO Evaluation scripts
provided by U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service. The shapefiles were then uploaded to the
soil data warehouse for archival and distribution.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NRCS13</srcused>
        <procdate>20130806</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20131216</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20131216</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined
that the tabular data should be released for official use. A
selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was
copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected
interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is
stored in the database table named sainterp.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20140805</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or
delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units
link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined
data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned
version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to
the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components
were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil
data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial
data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NASIS</srcused>
        <procdate>20140805</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.000001</latres>
        <longres>0.0000001</longres>
        <geogunit>decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>World Geodetic System 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>World Geodetic System 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.00000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Special Soil Features</enttypl>
        <enttypd>
Special Soil Features represent soil, miscellaneous area, or landform
features that are too small to be digitized as soil delineations
(area features).
</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Special Soil Features Codes</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Special Soil Features labels represent specific Special Soil
Features. These features are identified with a descriptive
label. The label is assigned to the point or line assigned
to represent the feature on maps.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>
Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS;
National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647
(current issue), USDA, NRCS.
</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>
Classification and Correlation of the Soils of Salt Lake Area,
Utah
</codesetn>
            <codesets>
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources
Conservation Service
</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>
Map Unit Delineations are closed polygons that may be dominated
by a single soil or miscellaneous area component plus allowable
similar or dissimilar soils, or they can be geographic mixtures
of groups of soils or soils and miscellaneous areas.

The map unit symbol uniquely identifies each closed map unit
delineation. Each symbol corresponds to a map unit name. The map
unit key is used to link to information in the National Soil
Information System tables.

Map Unit Delineations are described by the National Soil
Information System database. This attribute database gives the
proportionate extent of the component soils and the properties for
each soil. The database contains both estimated and measured data
on the physical and chemical soil properties and soil
interpretations for engineering, water management, recreation,
agronomic, woodland, range, and wildlife uses of the soil.

The National Soil Information System database contains static
metadata. It documents the data structure and includes such
information as what tables, columns, indexes, and relationships
are defined as well as a variety of attributes of each of these
database objects. Attributes include table and column
descriptions and detailed domain information.

The National Soil Information System database also contains a
distribution metadata. It records the criteria used for selecting
map units and components for inclusion in the set of distributed
data.

Special features are described in the feature table.  It includes
an area symbol, feature label, feature name, and feature description
for each special and ad hoc feature in the survey area.
</eaover>
      <eadetcit>
Soil Taxonomy: A basic system of soil classification for making and
interpreting soil surveys. Agricultural Handbook 436, 1999, USDA, SCS.

Keys to Soil Taxonomy (current issue), USDA, SCS.

National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647 (current
issue), USDA, NRCS.

Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS.
</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>
U.S. Department of Agriculture,
Natural Resources Conservation Service,
National Geospatial Center of Excellence
</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>501 West Felix Street, Building 23</address>
          <city>Fort Worth</city>
          <state>Texas</state>
          <postal>76115</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800 672 5559</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>202 720 2600</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>817 509 3469</cntfax>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Salt Lake Area, Utah SSURGO</resdesc>
    <distliab>
Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer
system at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, no warranty expressed
or implied is made by the Agency regarding the utility of the data
on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute
any such warranty. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will warrant
the delivery of this product in computer readable format, and will
offer appropriate adjustment of credit when the product is determined
unreadable by correctly adjusted computer input peripherals, or
when the physical medium is delivered in damaged condition. Request
for adjustment of credit must be made within 90 days from the date
of this shipment from the ordering site.

The U.S. Department of Agriculture, nor any of its agencies are
liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of
viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of
these data sets. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits
discrimination in all its programs and activities on the basis of race,
color, national origin, sex, religion, age, disability, political
beliefs, sexual orientation, or marital or family status. (Not all
prohibited bases apply to all programs.)
</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>ESRI shapefile</formname>
          <formcont>spatial</formcont>
          <transize>6.6</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>URL:http://DataGateway.nrcs.usda.gov/</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>
Select desired survey area at above Internet
Web site. An email address is required for receipt of
instructions on retrieval via anonymous FTP. Anticipate a
delay between submission of request at Web site and receipt of
email message.
</accinstr>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>
There is currently no direct charge for requesting data or for
retrieval via FTP.
</fees>
      <ordering>
Visit the above mentioned Internet Web Site, select state or
territory, then select individual soil survey area of interest.
Spatial line data and locations of special feature symbols are in
ESRI ArcGIS shapefile, format.
The National Soil Information System attribute soil data are available
in variable length, pipe delimited, ASCII file format.
</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Typically within four hours</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20141003</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>State Soil Scientist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>NRCS</address>
          <address>Federal Building, Room 4010</address>
          <address>125 South State</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>UT</state>
          <postal>84138-1100</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-524-4574</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>800-877-8339</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>801-524-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Mike.Domeier@ut.usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>